The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Seventeenth Episode
The Greedy Ghost
This is a truly
terrible story.
The deceased owner
of the house...
...was very miserly,
despite being rich,
and treated the poor terribly.
And is it true what they say: that now
there is a ghost living in the house?
That's right! It seems that it is
the owner herself...
...who continues to haunt
the house as a ghost.
- And do you believe it?
- Many people believe it.
What?! Where do you want to go, Your Highness?
It's already dark outside!
Besides, today's lesson
is not over yet!
That means you will do it.
Make sure you study hard!
Don't worry..
Hey, but I am the teacher!
Then teach yourself! Goodbye!
- Are you leaving? - I'm going to play
in the ghost's house.
No! I forbid you
to leave the castle!
Wait, Prince!
Don't go away!
Stop him! Stop
Prince Sapphire, quick!
He went to the ghost's house!
Did you hear, Baron?
It's the ghost's house
that everyone is talking about.
That's the one!
Follow him immediately
Yes, sir! Do I have to go
into that house too?
Why not? You often asked
to borrow money...
...from the owner,
before she died,
so you are a client
of the ghost, let's say! Go!
Damn, so much fog!
I can barely see anything anymore.
I have to go slower
It went out!
What's wrong with you? Are you scared?
Come on, don't be a scaredy-cat!
Look at me: I am not afraid
at all, even if I am a girl! See?
Did you get angry?
Good! Keep going!
Go back home, Opal.
I will spend a night here. Do
you think the ghost will hurt me?
Tomorrow morning you will
come pick me up. Don't worry.
Rest easy,
I don't need your help.
Don't worry!
Go home, now.
Bye, see you tomorrow!
Bye, Opal!
Where are you going? Wait! Wait!
You really are a terrible hat!
It's impossible
to cross this swamp!
Well, this way I have a good
excuse to get out of here.
I must consider myself
lucky. Let's head right back!
Help! I'm drowning!
Damn! I didn't know it was
so shallow.
But that is Opal!
Wait!
Hey, ghost! Show
yourself, if you're there!
This is truly
a supernatural event!
Damn, so many books!
Oh, there's a set table!
Now this is a surprise!
I'll taste this!
It's strange, it seems to
me that the bottle is moving!
I don't want to drink!
This must be a trick!
No! No! I don't want it!
I'm sure it's made
of mud and clay!
Well, it's good anyway.
Good!
Thank you! This is even
too much kindness!
Strange, though..! How come
the ghost treats me so well?
I saw your magic! Why
don't you show yourself?
It must be the portrait of the
owner. What a beautiful woman!
Who's there?
- You're quite the flatterer!
- Are you the ghost?!
- That's right, my handsome.
- You are older than the portrait.
- Yes, I was much younger there.
- But I'm surprised.
I thought ghosts
had a horrible appearance.
Usually that's the case
and it could be my case,
but I don't feel like looking
like an old witch...
..and I take care of my appearance.
Excuse me, but why
are you treating me so well?
I heard that in life
you were very stingy.
Yes, go ahead and say it.
What does it matter now, anyway?
I was the stingiest and greediest in the world!
And that is why
I cannot rest in peace!
Not even after my death!
And what's worse,
I cannot go to Heaven!
Why don't you give yourself a push
and go up?
You see, that's how you go to Heaven.
You whistle, the car arrives.
...and if you can go there,
it takes you on board.
But I have never been picked up!
Heaven is calling me.
Then you can go up to Heaven!
I'm afraid not.
The problem is not solved.
What a strange light this is..
Madam, I'll hold the light
for you, so you can climb up!
- There, now climb!
- Thank you!
It's slipping!
Did you hurt yourself,
Prince Sapphire?
Don't worry about me!
Climb as fast as you can!
You were right, they don't
want to let you reach Heaven.
It's too much for me!
I can't take it anymore!
I am desperate
and I even want to die!
The fact is that you cannot
die twice.
Oh, right, I had forgotten!
I wish I could help you,
but I don't know how.
I found it! Tell me, were there many
people at your funeral?
- I didn't have a funeral.
- That's exactly the point:
the funeral! We will need
a large number of people...
...to attend! How many
people were closest to you?
Let me think.
I had three dear friends,
whom I had known for many years.
Maybe that will be enough! I'm going to fetch them!
Tell me where they live!
But why do you think
that the funeral...
...will allow me
to go to Heaven?
Because everyone weeps for the deceased
during the funeral service.
I think that anyone
can go to Heaven...
.if people weep for him
Yes, but I have been
too wicked!
Oh, no! Forgive me!
I didn't mean that.
Here are their addresses
Here, this one here...
This one here and this other one here..!
I will ask them to come!
Drink this cordial
and do not be afraid of me.
You will remember that I lent you
some money. Did you bring it?
But... is she still talking about
money even though she's a ghost?!
Even a ghost remembers
the money she lent.
Oh, no! If I keep going like
this, I will never go to Heaven!
Are you really sure that
you can go to Heaven...
..if someone cries for you?
You eavesdropped, didn't
you? How indiscreet you are!
Listen, what would
you say if I cried for you?
Young man, if you are really
so kind, then please do it!
I am willing to
clear your debts.
First, I need another favor.
You don't want to borrow
more money from me again, I hope!
No, ma'am.
It's about Sapphire.
What does
Prince Sapphire have to do with it?
I would like you to find proof
that the Prince is a girl.
So, let's see...
This is the first one.
Hey, you! Did you borrow
some money from Mrs. Shannerock?
Damn, this is a stable!
Good heavens, what a scare!
- What happened, Sapphire?
- Tink, where are you?
I'm here! What are you doing?
Do you know why I'm here?
I'm looking for three people who..
...can weep for the death
of a certain old lady.
I see,
then I can help you too
- What do you want me to do?
- You go that way!
Alright!
Quick! We have to help a poor
old lady! Come with me!
Have you ever borrowed money
from Mrs. Shannerock?
I asked her for a penny, but I've
already returned it. Goodbye!
Why did you wake me up, little one?
I was sleeping so well!
- Mrs. Shannerock...
- She lent me a nickel...
...and died before I
could return it to her.
- Come with me! Right now!
- What a rush!
If you cry for her, she
will cancel your debt!
- Really?
- What do you want from me?!
Put me down! Put me
down, I said! Come on!
Please excuse him. Did
you know Mrs. Shannerock?
Yes, I knew her, and her greed
always made me feel very sorry for her.
Could you cry for her? Be kind!
Come with me to cry for her!
Very well!
I'll be happy to come.
...to this sort of funeral
whenever you want, even right now!
It's an excellent idea on your part!
You could cry for her, then!
Come to think of it, why should we
cry for that woman?
It's impossible! When she was alive, she didn't
even give us a piece of bread!
You mangy old man! You'll see!
Now I'm full.
I'm going home.
Can you cry a little for her,
before you go?
Even if I force myself,
can't you see I can't do it?
Hypocrite!
I couldn't pay her back
some money she lent me,
so she took my house, my
horse, and everything I had.
It's impossible for me to cry for her!
Good heavens! I'm afraid
that no one will want to cry for her.
At least you, who were her maid,
will try to cry, right?
No, I won't! She made me
work without paying me...
...and she didn't give me enough
to eat.
No wonder a person
like that is rejected by Heaven.
She deserves
to stay on Earth!
Mean! They are all mean!
This is too much for me,
even if I am a ghost!
I like money, it's true, but
what's wrong with loving money?
- Oh, no! You too!
- It's a hopeless endeavor!
Yes, maybe it's better if we leave
No, Prince! Please, stay
with me! Don't go away!
Why did you stop?
- I can't leave her like this.
- Do you want to go back, Sapphire?
What do you say, Opal?
See? Even Opal
agrees with me.
You can go back to the city
with Opal, Tink.
- Watch out for the ghost.
- Go, Opal!
Goodbye, Sapphire!
Alas! I am a lonely
and miserable ghost!
I am willing
to cry for you,
as long as you do me the favor
I asked of you some time ago.
But how do I get proof
that the Prince is a girl?
- Ah, there he is coming back!
- I expected it!
I am counting on you!
I am hiding!
Oh, Prince!
I am glad you have returned!
I thank you
for your kindness
Please, make yourself comfortable in my house.
Come! Follow me, Prince. Please.
But it is magnificent!
Look inside this wardrobe,
Prince.
I hope there are
some clothes that you like.
But you must be joking!
Those are all women's clothes!
I am a boy! Got it?
And I am a ghost!
So I know for sure whether
you are a girl or a boy.
This is not elegant enough.
This is too big.
This seems right!
- Please, stop!
- The mirror is at the end of the hall.
And now...
Welcome! I didn't expect to
see you here, Princess Sapphire!
Princess?!
For a Princess who
pretends to be a Prince...
...there is the death penalty in this kingdom!
- What? The death penalty?!
Which do you prefer?
Decapitation or hanging?
You cannot send
such a good person to death!
But this is decreed
by the law of Silverland,
against which
nothing can be done!
Are you ready, Princess?
I will take you to Grand Duke Duralumin!
I don't care at all
about this damn law!
I don't find it reasonable to send
such a good person to death!
I'm sorry, Prince Sapphire!
This man is very wicked.
He took advantage of my good
faith for his dirty schemes.
It seems my big mouth
woke him up.
I wonder what I bumped into!
Shall we go then, Princess?
- Princess? And where is she?
- What?!
I know you are a girl! I made
sure of it with my own eyes!
Oh, is that so? Then why don't you
make sure of it once more?
She must have changed...
Madam, you saw it too
that she is a girl! Didn't you?
- No!
- Did you hear?
Even this lady says... What?!
No! I assure you that Prince
Sapphire is without a doubt a boy!
But it's impossible!
Look at the clothes in the wardro..
Oh, no!
He was looking at himself in the mirr..
Damned old hag! You'll
pay for your betrayal!
I will forbid everyone
from coming to this house!
Do you know what that means? That
no one will come to weep for you,
so you will remain a ghost forever!
- No! Nylon!
- So, what is Sapphire?
Prince Sapphire is..
...it's... it's... it's...
it's really a boy!
You'll pay for this!
Why did you do it? It
was a good opportunity!
I don't know, Prince.
Really, I don't know!
Look! It's that light again!
It's the road to Heaven,
ma'am!
I'll try to climb up.
Thank you, Prince!
Watch out, ma'am!
Help! Someone help me!
I'm sorry that this time,
too, you didn't make it.
Prince, I hate Heaven!
Why is the other world
divided into Hell and Heaven?
What is this noise?
There he is! That is a
ghost! Set fire to the room!
- Let everything burn!
- Yes, sir!
Do you want to set the
house on fire?! I won't let you!
Damn Shannerock!
Soldiers, keep setting the fire!
Yes, sir!
Help!
Do you see? Evil
will strike your men...
...if they continue to
set fire to the house!
Don't listen to her!
Keep burning it!
Stop, Nylon! This is
an order from the Prince!
No, you are not a Prince! Your
Highness, you have given yourself away!
You are a girl! Quick,
arrest Princess Sapphire!
Alright, then I will stop them!
You, madam, put out the fire!
Be careful, madam!
It's over for this house!
Shannerock will end up
being a ghost without a home!
Without a home!
Get out of here! It's
dangerous to stay here!
Here I am! Let's get out
of here quickly! Let's go!
This is my home, Prince.
I am too tired to move.
Watch out!
Please, get out
of here! I will stay.
I am sorry to have disturbed you, but
by now I have given up on everything.
- Even on going to Heaven?
- Yes.
But now get out of here quickly! In
a little while this house will collapse.
Be careful! Nylon
is trying to kill you!
You worry about me...
at a moment like this?
Prince Sapphire, I
beg you! Be careful!
How sweet of you to worry so
much about me! I am so moved by it...!
Good heavens! The fire has
stopped burning! How is that?
Prince Sapphire, now
I can go to Heaven,
since you have shed
tears for me.
Please, leave this house now
that the fire is not burning!
Hurry!
- The Prince's ghost!
- Nylon!
Prince, I am overjoyed
that you were saved!
Anyway, excuse me, what
happened to the ghost of Shannerock?
Look! Mrs. Shannerock
is going up to Heaven!
Goodbye, ma'am!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP